<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Calgary Real Estate Podcast with Eric Mortimer</title>
    <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://localhost:4000"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Eric Mortimer & Associates - your professional Calgary Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Eric Mortimer</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2019-12-09 13:12:44 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Eric Mortimer</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Calgary, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>Eric@EricMortimer.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Eric Mortimer</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Eric Mortimer</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="http://localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Calgary, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Calgary Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Eric Mortimer & Associates - your professional Calgary Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>Eric Mortimer's Journey</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/eric-mortimers-journey.html</link>
        
        <author>Eric Mortimer</author>
        <pubDate>2019-12-09 08:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Hear how Eric Mortimer started his journey in real estate, how he overcame the struggles in the early years, and how real estate has changed his life.


</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Hear how Eric Mortimer started his journey in real estate, how he overcame the struggles in the early years, and how real estate has changed his life.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Eric Mortimer</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Hear how Eric Mortimer started his journey in real estate, how he overcame the struggles in the early years, and how real estate has changed his life.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Calgary, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Whom Are You Hanging With?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/whom-are-you-hanging-with.html</link>
        
        <author>Eric Mortimer</author>
        <pubDate>2019-12-05 08:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Are you 100% satisfied with all areas of your life? What if you could take a magic wand and change one or two areas - what would those things be?



For thousands of years, feng shui practicers know if you can change your environment, you can change your life. They would add or subtract things from the space. What’s funny though, is they would often miss the people in that equation. People can be poisoning you as well.

New research on goal contagion actually shows us that we will unconsciously adopt and start pursuing the goals of the people that surround us. Have you seen this in your life?

“The people we hang out with affects what you do, and who you become.”

As a kid, I had just graduated high school and started a construction business with my brothers. I started unconsciously started adopting self destructive behaviors. I didn’t have any real examples around me of people to show me the importance of personal growth or meaningful relationships. I thought, “this just isn’t going to cut it anymore. Something has to change.”

I left that environment and those influences, and in contrast now, I live my life by design. I spend my time with purpose driven people that have high values, and my life is spiraling up in all my life areas. I’ve been fortunate to build a business of being a top real estate agent, I have created events, coaching programs and transformation groups that have sold out in hours. And now these people are helping others and it keeps rippling.  If I can do it, as a lost construction worker from Ontario, than you can too.

One big reason for the shift is because I changed my friends. It’s who I do, and do not, hang around with.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Are you 100% satisfied with all areas of your life? What if you could take a magic wand and change one or two areas - what would those things be?

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Eric Mortimer</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Are you 100% satisfied with all areas of your life? What if you could take a magic wand and change one or two areas - what would those things be?

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Calgary, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Difference Working on a Real Estate Team Makes</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-difference-working-on-a-real-estate-team-makes.html</link>
        
          <category>Transaction Management</category>
        
        <author>Eric Mortimer</author>
        <pubDate>2019-11-17 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Is it better to work as part of a team or to work as a solo agent?

The real estate industry is challenging to work in right now, thanks to shifting market conditions, and this has left many agents looking for ways to put their careers back on track. If you’ve been working as a solo agent, perhaps the best route moving forward is to join a team.

But why? What’s so great about joining a team?

Well, first of all, while being a solo agent does mean you don’t have anyone to report to, this is actually a double-edged sword. Not reporting to anyone is great in concept, but can really damage your success and productivity in practice.

The first major benefit of working with a team is that, unlike working on your own, you’ll never be without guidance or support. Sure, you’re going to be held accountable to your potential—but isn’t that what you want?

Surrounding yourself with like-minded people who are real movers and shakers in the industry will always bring you greater success than trying to go it alone. You’ve probably heard of the idea that you’re the average of the five people you spend the most time with, and this is especially true in a professional setting. That’s the real value of being on a team—it will keep you accountable and help you grow.

“Surrounding yourself with like-minded people will always bring you greater success than trying to go it alone.”

But what about the fear of splitting a commission?

Think of it this way: Have you ever thought to yourself that FSBO sellers are making a mistake? After all, even though they’d have to pay a commission fee to hire an agent, they’d walk away with more money in their pocket at the end of the deal by doing so. The same applies for real estate professionals. You might have to sacrifice a small portion of your revenue to be part of a team, but that minor sacrifice actually goes toward giving you more resources and a greater opportunity to succeed. Beyond that, you’ll have a mentor working alongside you.

A lot of brokerages simply aren’t set up to offer this experience. Being on a team is truly unique in its advantages.

Of course, knowing what to do and actually doing it are two different things. It’s easy to go online and find advice about why you should join a team, but only you can take the necessary steps to follow through and do it.

As it happens, our team offers business planning workshops for just this reason. We want to help you act on your goals, so sign up for our next event soon. Find out more information about these workshops here!

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Is it better to work as part of a team or to work as a solo agent?</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Eric Mortimer</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Is it better to work as part of a team or to work as a solo agent?</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Calgary, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Eric Mortimer</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Eric Mortimer</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Eric Mortimer & Associates - your professional Calgary Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
